<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golf on Sportnomics</title>
    <link>/tags/golf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golf on Sportnomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/golf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PGA Analysis</title>
      <link>/2018/04/pga-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/pga-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Do PGA Golfers Preform Better in Different Regions or Rounds?Many times I hear either on TV or through friends that X golfer preforms better in round 4 or that X golfer seems to play better in the south. Intuitively I can see the case for both, some golfers may preform better on a given round due to their mindset. It is even easier to understand that players may play better in a given region, due to being in an area they are comfortable with or grew up and where they are more familiar with the typical layouts of courses or the grass of the course so lets look into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Golf Scores Database</title>
      <link>/2017/08/creating-golf-scores-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/creating-golf-scores-database/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this post is to create a database with all the scores recorded on golf tours. ESPN holds all the scorecards of players for each tournament dating back to 2001.
We are going to start out by exploring around the ESPN website to find out how the data is stored and a way to scrape the data into R and then we are going to export this big data to SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping PGA Site</title>
      <link>/2017/07/scraping-pga-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/scraping-pga-site/</guid>
      <description>To begin we want to use the json data from the PGA tour website. After doing some investigation into the PGA tour website, there are both pros and cons of using it for scraping.
From what I have found we will only be able to get shot data from 2014 and beyond. This will contain any data we would want but only goes back to 2014, before 2014 there isn’t even data for simple scorecards for players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hole Cloud</title>
      <link>/2017/07/the-hole-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/the-hole-cloud/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will create word clouds to help determine what may or may not be important in predicting PGA golfers performance. I will start with gathering data from the PGA tour website.

In this example I will be using descriptions from TPC Sawgrass golf course which hosts the Players Championship every year and is one of the most iconic course in the game. The hole descriptions in website format can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>